inspiration.com 2018-11-08

# Inspiration Software, Inc. Privacy Policy | inspiration.com

**_Inspiration Software, Inc. (“Inspiration”) is committed to protecting your privacy when you access and use our inspiration.com web site (the “Site”) and provides you this notice that any data or information collected and used by Inspiration in connection with the Site and products, content, or services made available or enabled via the Site (“Products”, “Content” and “Services”) are governed by this online privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) as amended from time to time, and not any privacy in effect at the time the data and information was collected. Please regularly review our Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not govern privacy practices associated with any other web site (including any web sites linked to), offline activities or other products, services or materials not available or enabled by this Site. This Site, Products, Content and Services made available or enabled by the Site are intended for adult audiences, and Inspiration does not knowingly collect any personal information from anyone under 13 years of age._**

 **

  * CHANGES IN PRIVACY POLICY
  * PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * GDPR

**

While it is not Inspiration’s practice to collect and store personal information from Site users, any information that identifies or can be used to indentify the person to whom such information pertains (“personal information”) that may be collected or stored will be subject to this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time. Inspiration may change this Privacy Policy from time to time in its sole discretion and will provide notice of changes in the Privacy Policy and on the Site’s home page. If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue use of the Site, Products, Content and Services made available or enabled by the Site. Users of the Site will be deemed to have been made aware of, and will be subject to the changes to the Privacy Policy after Inspiration has posted any notice of changes in the Privacy Policy and on the Site’s home page.

Inspiration is committed to respecting your legal rights with respect to your personal information. Except in particular circumstances described in this Privacy Policy, or where required by law, regulation, litigation, national security or law enforcement, Inspiration will not provide your name to other companies or organizations without your consent.

Inspiration is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any non-Inspiration web sites to which this Site, Products, Content or Services may link. You are strongly advised to review the privacy policy(ies) of any of these sites before using them.

Inspiration also adheres to European Union Safe harbor principles as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information covered by the Privacy Policy from the European Union.

As you access and use the Site, Products, Content and Products, Inspiration may from time to time ask you to provide certain information and data about yourself by filling out and submitting a form or a field on the Site. This information could include for example your first and last name, mailing address, country of residence, e-mail address, telephone or facsimile number, work address and other information. Of course, it is optional for you to provide such information, however, in some instances Inspiration may require certain mandatory information about you in order for you to gain access to or use the Site, Products, Content and Services. If you do not provide mandatory data and information with respect to that particular access to or use of the Site, Products, Content and Services, you will not be able to access or use the Site, the Products, Content and Services.

In order to facilitate our evaluation of your use of the Site, Products, Content and Services, Inspiration will also from time to time collect information about your computer which may include among other information, its operating system, CPU speed, Internet Protocol (IP) address, referring or exit web pages and browser type. Inspiration will use this information to measure your use of the Site, Products, Content and Services to support, evaluate, enhance and supplement your user experience with any or all of them. We do not match or link this information with any other information held by Inspiration without your prior consent.

In addition, Inspiration may choose to supplement the personal information you provide to us with information about you available from other third party sources. Where permitted by law, we may, for example, supplement your Registration Information with address information provided by the U.S. Post Office to maintain and improve performance of our data base, authenticate users and/or prevent abuse of the Site, Products, Content and Services. We may also supplement the information you submit to us with demographic or other information (e.g. age and/or interests) stored in third party databases to better focus and enhance and marketing or other communications we send to you about the Site, Products, Content and Services that we feel may be of interest to you.

In some instances, Inspiration may choose to link from the Site to various third party vendors and service providers who may have products or services that our Site users might find useful, such as those that can be used with or are compatible with the Services and Materials accessible from or enabled by the Site. In order to use any products or services from such third parties you may be required to provide personal information to such third parties. In such event, any personal information you provide to these third parties will be subject to the privacy policy posted on their web site.

_Cookies, web beacons and similar tracking devices_

Inspiration may use cookies, web beacons or other devices to track your use of the Site, the Services or the Materials (e.g. types of Services or Materials used, number of uses or downloads, number of users of the Site, the Services or the Materials) and our web servers will automatically log the IP/Internet address of your computer. This information is collected in aggregate form, without identifying any use individually. Inspiration may use this aggregated information to for improving and enhancing the Site, the Services and Materials and for statistical analysis. It is not Inspiration’s practice to use this information for any other purposes or to identify any user personally, however, where you have expressly provided consent for the Site, the Services or the Materials to “remember” the unique identifier that you select when you register your account, that unique identifier will be stored on a cookie on your computer and that unique identifier will be linked to your Registration Information. For your information and understanding, a cookie is a small amount of data that is transferred to your browser by a web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It serves as your ID card and enables the web server that gave it to you to record your passwords and preferences. A web beacon is a small gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or email used to track when the page or email has been viewed. Similar devices can be embedded in the Services or Materials to send data to a web server when a set of user-initiated events occur, as when a user clicks on one or more buttons to initiate an action, direction or response on the Site.

Most browsers default to allow or accept cookies, and most products and services that include similar devices also default to activate or allow the collection of data. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the option to decide whether or not to accept it (however, some web pages, including those that may be contained in web sites linked to this Site, may require an authorization and may not grant you the option of choosing not to accept cookies or similar devices and will likely not allow you to access those pages or any related products or services).

You are also advised that some products and services, including some of the Products, Content and Services on this Site may allow document authors to restrict access to documents, track access to or use of those documents, or involve transmission of data over the Internet to verify authenticity of authors, recipients and documents. Where this type of tracking is not obvious to you, the software and/or services license or terms of use, pop-ups or notifying e-mail will inform you of these features and of any options available to you to disable the features.

When Inspiration collects your personal information, it does so to support, record, facilitate and enhance your use of the Site, Products, Content and Services. Except where prohibited by law or where you have opted to not receive such communications, we may also use your personal information to track your use and preferences and to keep you informed about product and service upgrades, and other products and services of Inspiration, its partner vendors and partner service providers and other third parties.

Inspiration classifies any personal information that you submit and provide in connection with your use of the Site, Products, Content and Services as “User Information.” Your User Information is protected in the following ways:

**

  * TRANSFERS OF INFORMATION TO SUCCESSORS AND ASSIGNS
  * NOTICE REGARDING COMMUNITY SITES
  * COMPLAINTS

**

You acknowledge and agree that if Inspiration sells or assigns assets (or the assets of any division or subsidiary) to another entity, or Inspiration (or a division or subsidiary) is acquired by or merged with another entity, Inspiration may provide to such entity customer information that is related to that part of our business that was sold to, assigned to, or merged with the other entity without obtaining your further consent, but Inspiration will provide notice of such asset sales, assignments, acquisitions, or mergers on the Site.

This Site may link to one or more Community Sites. Any information that you post to a public chat room, blog, bulletin board, or to community help, wikis, personal sharing URLs and user profiles (“Community Sites”) will be available to all users accessing that location, and your e-mail address and other personal information and content you upload may also be posted on these Community Sites. The information you share by posting to the Community Sites may be read, collected or used by other users accessing these Community Sites for any purpose including sending you unsolicited message or Spam. Inspiration is not responsible for any information you elect to submit to these Community Sites, the uses of that information or the consequences to you resulting from the use of that information.

If you feel that Inspiration has failed to comply with its obligations under this Privacy Policy or otherwise have complaints with respect to Inspiration’s use or protection of your personal information, you may fill out a Privacy Complaint form and send it to Inspiration’s Privacy Officer at the following address:

Inspiration Software, Inc.   
Attn: Privacy Officer   
6443 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Hwy, Suite 370   
Portland, Oregon 97221   
USA

Please be specific in your complaint and provide as much detail as possible so that we can promptly address your concerns. We will investigate and respond to all complaints promptly.
